shoutable.com 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy - Shoutable

**Shoutable.com Privacy Policy**

**As of May 25, 2018  
**  

Shoutable.com has prepared this Privacy Policy to help you understand more about how we collect, use, and disclose information that we collect about consumers through our web and mobile services, which we refer to in this Privacy Policy collectively as the “Services.”

This Privacy Policy does not cover information that we collect about you outside of our normal consumer services. For example, it does not cover information that we collect in news reporting or as a part of our business arrangements. Also, this Privacy Policy does not cover information that you voluntarily make public, such as by posting it in a publicly accessible place on the Internet.

**What information do you collect about me?**

The information that we collect about you falls into these general categories:

• Information that you provide. We may collect information that you choose to provide to us (including content that you submit to us or when you subscribe to our newsletter(s)). This may include information such as your name, e-mail address, phone number, year of birth, gender, zip code, country, postal address, user name, password, and password reminder questions and answers. We may ask you for information when you register or subscribe, or at other times—such as when you enter a contest, take a survey, participate in a promotion, provide content, or order products from us. We may be required by law to collect certain personal information about you or as a consequence of any contractual relationship we have with you. Failure to provide this information may prevent or delay the fulfillment of these obligations.

• Automated information. Using technologies that are widely used on the Internet, such as cookies, web beacons, and other technologies, we also may automatically collect information about your computer or mobile device and online activity when you access the Services. For example, when you visit [shoutable.com](http://shoutable.com/), we may collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and operating system, as well as information about which pages you visit and the page, if any, that referred you to our sites or that you visit after our sites. Similarly, when you use our mobile applications, we may collect information about your mobile device, such as the type of mobile device you use or your device identifier.

• Location information. When you use the Services, we may collect information about your location separately from your address or other information that you provide to us explicitly. For instance, we may use the GPS feature of your mobile device or your IP address to help determine your geographic location. If you prefer that we not know your geographic location, you will have the option to disable the function when you first use the service in which we collect information about your location (or later, if your mobile device allows you to change the settings after initial download). Disabling the geolocation function may prevent you from using certain features of our Services that require location information.

• Social networking information. If you log-in to Shoutable through a social networking account (e.g., Facebook or Twitter), we may collect information about you from that social networking account, including your name, email address, birthday, profile photograph, and other information associated with your social networking account.

**How do you use this information?**

We use the information that we collect about you for these purposes:

• for editorial purposes, such as in connection with our news reporting;

• to contact you to provide information about Shoutable or other products or services in which we believe you may be interested, including legal notices or information about changes to this policy

• to manage your account;

• to provide you with the products and services you request;

• to respond to your requests, questions, and comments;

• to perform business analyses or for other purposes to improve the quality of our business, the products and services we offer, including through surveys and questionnaires;

• to deliver targeted advertising, as described below;

• as we believe is necessary to protect our rights and the rights of others, including by enforcing our terms;

• and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.;

We also do research on our users’ demographics, interests, and behavior to help us operate our services, for other business purposes, and in connection with our display of advertising. This research is based on the information you provide to us including upon registration during a promotion, in surveys, and on your use of our services.

**With whom do you share this information?**

We may share the information that we collect about you through the Services in these ways:

• with authorized service providers that help us provide the Services or perform other business functions for us, such as sending emails or hosting web services (but these service providers are not permitted to use personally identifiable information that we provide for any purpose other than to provide service to us);

• with our corporate affiliates, licensees, and contractors;

• in the context of contests or other promotions in which we identify an outside entity, with the identified entity;

• to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process, in response to a request for cooperation from law enforcement or another government agency, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;

• when we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or as otherwise required by law;

• to enforce our terms and other agreements, or otherwise protect or defend our rights or property or the rights or property of others, or the safety of the public;

• in connection with a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale;

• in aggregated or other non-personally identifiable form;

• and as otherwise described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent.

In addition, if you provide content to the Services, such as submitting a comment, any information that you submit will become public. It may become accessible through search engines or, if you sign in using credentials from a third-party social networking service, to users on that service. Unless otherwise noted, we do not limit the distribution of information that you share using these features.

**How do you decide which advertisements to show me on the Services?**

The Services are offered to you free of charge because we cover the cost of providing our Services by displaying advertisements. Many of these advertisements are targeted, which means that advertisers tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, men over 25 years old). We will display the advertisement to users meeting those criteria, but we never provide the advertiser with information about the specific individuals who receive the ads. The targeted ads on the Services may be provided by us, or they may be provided by a third-party vendor. We may use automated decision-making to customize your experience based on your personal information. 

We also participate in affiliate advertising and allow affiliate links to be encoded on some of our pages. This means that we may earn a commission when you click on or make purchases via affiliate links and affiliate partners may use cookies to understand your use of the Services.

**Does this  Privacy Policy apply to information collected through third-party offerings?**

We sometimes partner with third parties that operate platforms or offer services that you can use to access or otherwise interact with our content and offerings. For example, you can access Shoutable on your Apple iPad or iPhone. Similarly, we may include in some of our Services features that integrate with third-party social networking services or other third-party services. To do this, we may include in our web pages and apps code from the social networking service provider or other third party. This code may allow the service provider to collect information about your activities. If you are logged into social networking or other third-party services at the time, the service providers may also be able to identify you in connection with that information.

Although this Privacy Policy will apply to our use of information collected about you through these co-branded offerings, we do not control the privacy practices of our third-party partners. As a result, we want you to be aware that when you use these offerings you may be providing information to both us and our partner, and you should review the partner’s privacy policy to be sure that you know how it will use any data that it collects.

Shoutable contains links to other sites, including third party payment processors and affiliate marketing links encoded by third parties. Please be aware that Shoutable is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Shoutable. If you choose to purchase a product or service via our site, some special terms apply. Payments are handled by a third party payment processor, whose own terms and privacy policy will govern your transaction. We do not process, record or maintain your credit card, bank account or payment information, though the third party payment processor and/or the merchant may provide us with some data relating to your order, such as what you purchased and how much you spent, etc. We expressly disclaim any and all liability related to your use of any third party payment processor’s system, including its privacy practices. Also, we are not responsible for any fulfillment of product that you purchase from merchants or any issues relating to such product(s) or customer service.

**How do you protect the security of the information you store?**

We have in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect through the Services. However, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of our database, nor can we guarantee that the information you supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to us via the Services. Please refer to the U.S. Federal Trade Commission’s website for information on how to protect yourself from identity theft.

**How long do you keep the information you collect from me?**

We retain the information we collect about and from you for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose we collected it for and for the purpose of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information we process, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your information, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

In some circumstances we may aggregate and de-identify your information in such a way that you may not reasonably be re-identified by us or any other company in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.

**What rights do I have regarding data about me?**

If you would like to access, review, revise or delete personal information we have collected from you, please contact us as provided below. Your specific rights regarding access, review, revision or deletion your information is proscribed by local laws. Specific applicable local laws may be outlined below.

Legal rights applicable to personal data collected from residents of the European Economic Area: Pursuant to the EU General Data Protection Regulation, natural persons (called data subjects) are afforded certain rights regarding their personal data, including the right access, correct, delete, restrict or object to our use of, and receive a portable copy in a usable electronic format of your personal information. You also may have the right withdraw any consent that you have previously provided to us and to lodge a complaint with your local data protection or privacy regulator.

If you would like to exercise any of the above rights, and the law of your jurisdiction requires us to honor that request, please send your request in writing to the address below. To assist us in processing your request in timely manner, please make your request in English if you are able to do so. Your request should include any information relevant to your request, including, without limitation: (i) your name, email and postal address; (ii) the specific right you are asserting (e.g., removal); and (iii) if you are requesting removal, a brief explanation of why you believe such information should be removed.

To help us prevent fraudulent removal requests, please also include a legible copy of a document that verifies your identity. You need not provide a government-issued document; a utility bill or similar mailing will suffice. You may also obscure parts of the document such as identifying numbers so long as the document continues to clearly identify you. If you are making the request on behalf of another person, please indicate your relationship to that person and provide evidence of your authority to make such request. All requests for removal will be reviewed by Shoutable’s legal and compliance team and we reserve the right, in compliance with applicable laws, to accept or reject, or make further inquiries regarding, any requests.

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

**Do you collect information from children?**

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database promptly.

**What are my California  privacy rights?**

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about what personal information a company shares with third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. Upon receipt of this notification, we will discontinue sharing your information for third party direct marketing purposes as soon as practicable.

**What are cookies and web beacons and how are they used on the Services?**

We use cookies and other technologies to store information on your computer or mobile device. We use this information for a variety of purposes, such as to remember you when you return to our websites or to identify your activities as you use certain Services. To do this, we may store a unique identifier on your computer or device. As described above, advertising service vendors that serve ads into our sites may also use their own cookies or identifiers.

You may opt-out of the browser cookies delivered through the Services by changing the setting on your browser. Please be aware that this will disable all cookies delivered to your browser, not just the ones that we deliver, and that you may not be able to use all of the Services if you do not allow the placement of cookies. Also, opting out of browser cookies will not disable other technologies that we may use to collect information from you, including “Flash cookies.”

We or our third-party partners also may use technologies called web beacons that communicate information from your Internet browser to a web server. Web beacons can be embedded in web pages, videos, or emails, and can allow a web server to read certain types of information from your browser, check whether you have viewed a particular web page or email message, and determine, among other things, the time and date on which you viewed the web beacon, the IP address of your computer, and the URL of the web page from which the web beacon was viewed. We and our partners use web beacons for a variety of purposes, including analyzing the use of the Services and in conjunction with cookies to provide content and ads that are more relevant to you. You may disable our web beacons in email messages by turning off images in your email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see the instructions for your particular email client for more information. Please also be aware that by turning off images you may not be able to enjoy all of the Services as they were designed to be viewed.

**What choices do I have regarding your use of information about me?**

Email messages. If you do not wish to receive emailed promotional material from us, you can email us at [info@shoutable.com](mailto:info@shoutable.com). Please note that, even if you opt out of receiving promotional emails from us, we may still contact you to provide you with non-commercial messages, such as legal notices. Also, if you opt out, we may not provide to you non-promotional material, such as our emailed newsletters and other content.

Targeted advertising. If you would prefer not to receive advertisements through the Services that are targeted to your interests, you can inform our advertising vendor, Google, Inc., of your preference by clicking the “Opt out” button at [www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html) You also can manage your advertising preferences at [www.google.com/ads/preferences/](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences). In some cases, we and advertisers on the Services work with other third-party vendors to help deliver advertisements targeted to your interests. These vendors include ad networks and analytics providers, and they use cookies or other technologies to collect information about your online activity (e.g., the sites and pages you have visited) in order to help advertisers deliver particular ads that they believe you would find most relevant. Many third-party vendors that perform these functions are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, and you can opt out of those vendors’ delivery of targeted advertising to you by visiting [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and [www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). Some of our Services use technology for this purpose provided by Adobe. You can express your preferences regarding Adobe’s use of information about you here.

Please note that, because these opt-out tools will place a cookie on your computer to record your opt-out preference, any actions you take using these tools will apply only to the web browser that you use to take the action. Also, these tools may not work as expected if you set your browser to refuse cookies.

Sometimes, our advertisers will contract with a third-party service to host their ads. In this case, an ad-serving vendor contacts the advertisers’ hosting service to obtain a particular advertisement. Because we do not have a relationship with these third parties, we do not have a mechanism to allow visitors to opt out of tracking by these vendors.

**Is my data transferred internationally?**

Shoutable.com is headquartered in the United States. Please be aware that information you provide to us or we obtain as a result of your use of the Services may be collected in your country and subsequently transferred to the United States or another country in accordance with applicable law. The privacy and data protection laws in another country may not be equivalent to such laws in your country of residence. By using and participating in the Services or providing us with your information, you consent to the collection, international transfer, storage, and processing of your information.

**What happens when this  Privacy Policy changes?**

We may update this Privacy Policy in the future. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the e-mail address you provided to us or by placing a notice on the Shoutable website.

**Who should I contact if I have questions about this  Privacy Policy?**

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, you may contact us at: [info@shoutable.com](mailto:info@shoutable.com)

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the manner in which your information is processed or would like to submit a request to us, please contact:

Shoutable.com is the controller (as provided under laws applicable to EEA jurisdictions) responsible for the personal information we collect and process. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding the way in which your personal information collected in the EEA is processed, please contact us at [info@shoutable.com](mailto:info@shoutable.com)

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. If, however, you believe that we have not been able to assist with your complaint or concern, you may have the right to make a complaint to the data protection authority of your country of residence.
